Crown Princess, let me do it
太子妃 还是我来吧
You are slow
你太慢了
I'm good at this
这个我比较在行
Your Highness Miss Yao, she
殿下 姚姑娘她
I told you not to mention this person
我不是说了不要提及此人吗
Out
出去
Yes
是
Your Highness
殿下
Nothing
没事
Your Highness is worried about King Wei's illness
殿下是担心卫王的病情吧
Now the whole hospital is there
如今整个太医院都守在那儿
And what can happen
又能有什么事
Your Highness is worried too much
殿下是忧心过甚了
Zi Jin
子衿
In order to save Meng Shangshi and Yin Ziping,
你为了救孟尚食和殷紫萍
Willing to bear the responsibility of the staff
竟甘愿承受杖责
Is it worth it
值得吗
Do what you have to do
做该做的事
Save the person who should be saved
救该救的人
Whatever the consequences
不管何种后果
I am willing to accept it
我甘愿领受
What is it worth? Is it worth it
这有什么值不值得
Miyagi's staff can be very tight
宫正司手下的杖可厉害得紧
I told them just now
刚才我跟他们说了
The Empress does not want to see you again
皇后娘娘不想再见到你
Can you make it
你能熬得住吗
It's not too late for you to regret it now
你现在后悔还来得及
I will ask the Empress to drive you out of the palace
我会奏请皇后娘娘逐你出宫
Leave you alive
留你一条命
Didn't you send the eunuch who killed people
那杀人的宦官不就是你派来的吗
By mistake, I was allowed to escape
阴差阳错反容我逃过一劫
It's now
事到如今了
Why do you say anything against your will
干吗还要再说违心的话呢
I don't want to see you die with my own eyes
我不想亲眼看到你死
It's just
只是
It's fate
这是命
Take a few sticks
受了几杖
Only six sticks
才六杖
You can't stand just six sticks
区区六杖你已受不了了
Four more sticks
再来四杖
There will be no more you in the world
世上不会再有你这个人
As long as you bow your head and beg for mercy
只要你肯低头求饶
Say you are wrong
说一声你错了
This cane
这杖刑
You can get through it alive
你便能活着挨过
Dare to ask my Lord
敢问大人
What's wrong with me
我何错之有
Clearly familiar with things
明明通晓事理
See through the evil of human nature
看透人性之恶
But I still risked my own life to save others
却还是为救他人不顾自家性命
Isn't that wrong enough
这还不够错吗
If you don't know how to look back
你要是再不知回首
Even if I save you once,
纵然我救你一次
Soon you will make the same mistake again
很快你便会重蹈覆辙
And I never save people who take the initiative to die
而我从不救主动寻死之人
Continue
继续
Be ungrateful
不知好歹
Your Excellency
大人
It looks soft and weak
看起来柔柔弱弱的
Who knew the gas was so big
谁知道气性这么大
Your Excellency
大人
Such a disobedient woman dies when she dies
这么不听话的女人死就死了吧
Why keep it in mind
何必挂在心上呢
Find your own way to death
自寻死路
Telling you again and again
告诫你一次又一次
Why don't you listen to advice
为何就是不听劝告
Your Excellency
大人
Stop
住手
Girl, you just have to say
姑娘 你只要说一声
Your Highness will save you naturally
殿下自然会救你
Thank you for your kindness
多谢你的好意
And two sticks
还有两杖
I can stand it
我受得起
You don't have to plead
不用你开口求情
Even if you look up at your highness,
你哪怕抬起头看殿下一眼
Even if it's soft
就算是服个软
Your Highness, this
殿下 这
Continue
继续
Your Highness has already prescribed medicine for Yao's palm meal
殿下 已经为姚掌膳上过药了
Seasonal medicine
季典药
The medicine she takes every day
她每日服用的药剂
It's all suffered by you yourself
都由您亲自煎熬
And then send it to Shangshi Bureau
再送去尚食局
Yes
是
I don't want to be your concubine
我不愿做你的妃嫔
I don't want to live for you all my life
我也不愿终身为你而活
I don't want to be a puppet around others.
我更不愿成为别人左右的傀儡
Your Highness
殿下
Why don't you show up when you help people
为何帮人却不现身啊
Your Highness, don't you want to face
殿下不要颜面了吗
It involves Wei Wang
事涉卫王
It's time to find out
该查个水落石出
As for her life or death, what do I have to do with it
至于她的死活又与我何干
Your Highness is absolutely right
殿下所言极是
Where's the man you're looking for
让你寻的人呢
Someone has been invited
已着人去请
Father
父皇
I hope this time you
但愿你这一回
Don't let my son down again
不要再让儿臣失望
You're awake
你醒了
I'll help you
我扶你
Help her out
扶她出来
Yes
是
Come
来
I hold you
我扶着你
Thank you very much
多谢
Handmaiden visits empress
奴婢拜见皇后娘娘
Do you remember what I said to you
我对你说的话你还记得吗
Never forget for life
终身不忘
Why do you redress others' grievances
为何替他人申冤
Do not hesitate to endure such suffering
不惜忍受如此苦楚
Back to the empress's words
回皇后娘娘的话
That's nobody else
那不是别人
It is an adult who teaches handmaiden cooking
是教奴婢厨艺的尚食大人
And close friends
和至交好友
You want to redress your grievances
你要申冤
Where is the evidence
证据何在
Empress Empress
皇后娘娘
When cooking, the handmaiden was not in the kitchen
制膳当时 奴婢不在膳房
But the handmaiden knows
但奴婢知道
From Choosing Vegetables to Making Meals
从选菜到制膳
The food bureau has strict regulations
尚食局都有严格的章程
There will be no such mistakes
不会出现这样的纰漏
The Empress is asking you for evidence
皇后娘娘是在问你证据
Handmaiden has no evidence
奴婢没有证据
Empress Empress
皇后娘娘
There is an important sentence that must be reported in person
有句要紧的话定要当面禀报
No matter what the cause of His Royal Highness, King Wei
无论卫王殿下病因为何
This time, the empress can't get away with it
此番皇后娘娘都脱不开干系
Why
为什么
Cooking time
制膳时
The Queen once sent people to the dining room
皇后曾遣人来过膳房
Who are you talking about
你说的是谁
Your Majesty, you know well
陛下 您心知肚明
Why ask male and female servants and concubines
又何必来问臣妾呢
Bold
大胆
Your Majesty
陛下
The past is vivid in my mind
这往事历历在目
You are the king of a country
您是一国之君
Naturally, she dare not blame you
她自然不敢怪罪您
She is putting all her hatred
她这是将所有的仇恨
It's all recorded in the male and female servants
都记在了臣妾的身上
To begin
要动手
Just come at me
冲着我来就好了
Ayan
阿埏
Ayan, he is still a child
阿埏他还是个孩子
How can she be ruthless
她怎么能狠得下心呢
Guo Guifei said just now
郭贵妃刚才说
Who gave the hand to King Wei
是谁对卫王下的手啊
Your Majesty's handmaiden is dead
陛下 奴婢万死
Failed to stop the empress
没能拦住皇后娘娘
Since the imperial concubine has doubts,
既然贵妃心有疑虑
Why don't you confront me face to face
何不与我当面对质
Your Majesty
陛下
How is Wei Wang's condition
卫王病情如何
What did the doctor say
太医怎么说呀
When will the child wake up
孩子何时能醒
Don't touch him
不准碰他
Empress Empress
皇后娘娘
The other day
前些日子
I listened to what others said
我是听信了他人言
Almost lead to great disaster
险些酿成大祸
But I pleaded guilty to you again and again afterwards
但事后我再三向您请罪
Even if you have resentment
就算你有怨恨
You have to take care of your majesty, too
你也得顾及一下陛下呀
Your Majesty
陛下
The imperial concubine has no evidence and speculates
贵妃全无实据 妄加臆测
You can't believe it at all
您竟也全然相信
Your Majesty
陛下
Xuan Sheng Tai Yi
宣盛太医
Sheng Yin, a quack, has repeatedly broken the ban
庸医盛寅屡次犯禁
I have already dismissed him
朕早已将他革职
Don't talk about him again in the future
今后不许再言他
Your Majesty
陛下
Would you rather trust a bunch of quacks
您宁肯相信一群庸医
And dismiss the man who saved your wife's life
也要把救了您妻子命的人革职
Prince Prince and Princess arrived
太子 太子妃到
Father
父皇
Shengyin is not far from Beijing
盛寅离京不远
My son has urgently ordered him to return to Beijing
儿臣已经急命他返京
Diagnosis and treatment for Xiaoshi
为小十诊治
Zhu Zhanji
朱瞻基
Who allowed you to be so rebellious
谁准许你如此悖逆
Your Majesty, please allow my daughter-in-law to feel the pulse of King Wei
陛下 请允许臣媳为卫王诊脉
Go ahead
去吧
You
你
What are you going to do
你要干什么
Don't you touch my son
你别碰我儿子
Your Majesty
陛下
Zhu Zhanji
朱瞻基
Do you want to take your brother's life
难道要取你弟性命不成
His Royal Highness the Prince
太子殿下
Tai Hospital has already made a conclusion
太医院早已有了定论
His Royal Highness King Wei was poisoned
卫王殿下是因为中了毒
Will be unconscious
才会昏迷不醒
Why should you make your majesty angry again
您又何必再惹陛下生气呢
Father
父皇
Ayan is not you
阿埏不是您
I'm not a second uncle either
我也不是二叔
You
你
Ayan is my own brother
阿埏是我亲弟弟
I won't let anyone hurt him
我不会让任何人伤害他
What do you mean
你什么意思
I am Ayan's biological mother
我是阿埏的亲生母亲
Am I going to hurt him
难道我会伤害他吗
Your Majesty
陛下
King Wei is really not poisoned
卫王的确不是中毒
It's exogenous rheumatism and fire toxin that gives birth to back gangrene
而是外感风湿火毒 生了背疽
What are you talking about
你胡说八道什么
Just now, Dai Yuan judged clearly that
刚才戴院判分明说
Wei Wang is because he ate it
卫王是因为食用了
Unpoisoned antler
未净毒的鹿角菜
Are you sure
确定吗
Bearer
来人
Arrest Dai Yuan's sentence and torture him
把戴院判抓起来 严刑拷问
Yes
是
Zhu Zhanji
朱瞻基
How dare you give orders when I am here
朕在此 你竟敢发号施令
Father
父皇
Dorsal gangrene can endanger life
背疽可危害到性命
Dai Yuan was sentenced to old eyes again
戴院判再老眼昏花
How can it not be diagnosed
怎么可能诊不出来
Unless someone wants to deliberately conceal Xiao Shi's illness
除非有人想蓄意隐瞒小十的病情
You
你
Your Majesty, he
陛下 他
Father
父皇
Dai Yuan was sentenced to deceiving the superior and deceiving the inferior
戴院判欺上瞒下
According to your wisdom
依您的睿智
How can you think of the key
怎会想不到关键
It's just partial listening and partial believing
不过是偏听偏信罢了
Your Majesty
陛下
You can't believe this heart-wrenching statement
您万不可信这诛心之言啊
Back gangrene can kill a child at any time
背疽随时可以夺去孩子的性命
You're still here arguing
你还在这儿狡辩
Kwok, are you still worthy of being a mother
郭氏 你还配做个母亲吗
I
我
Father, Xiao Shi, I want to take it away
父皇 小十我要带走
In my palace to recuperate
就在我的宫里养病
As for the Imperial Concubine
至于贵妃
She is your concubine
她是您的妃嫔
It is inconvenient for children to interfere
儿臣不便干涉
Xiao Shi
小十
Come
来
Get up
起来
Ayan
阿埏
Your Majesty
陛下
You get up and drive
你起开
Ayan
阿埏
Come
来
Crown Princess
太子妃
Out
出去
I want to know the secret in her heart now
她心中的秘密我现在便要知道
Quack
庸医
So afraid of taking a pulse
如此畏惧诊脉
Why didn't you tell me what happened in the first place
为何不将当初的事情告诉我
Your Highness
殿下
My body knows it's wrong
妾身知错了
I'm sorry
对不起
Okay, I got it
好了 我知道了
I don't know what I did wrong
不知我犯了何错
Why won't the Queen see me
皇后为何不肯见我
Do you know that
你可知道
Yao Ziliao met the Empress that day
姚子衿那日见过皇后娘娘
What did she say
她说了什么
She said
她说
It's hard to excuse the Queen's involvement
皇后身涉其中 难以开脱
What else is there
还有什么
On the day of the incident
事发当日
Hu Shangshi was the first to identify antler as poisonous
胡尚食第一个指认出鹿角菜有毒
Will involve a lot of right and wrong
才会牵扯出诸多是非
This is a misunderstanding
这是误会
I didn't expect it at all
我根本未曾料到
Guo Guifei will treat Wei Wang's illness
郭贵妃会将卫王病情
Write it down to the empress
记在皇后娘娘身上
You naturally spare no effort to fight against dissidents
你为了打击异己 自然不遗余力
It's a pity that it's stupid to involve the Lord
可惜累及主上 实在愚不可及
Empress has a purport
皇后娘娘有旨
I have made a mistake of talking too much
既犯了言多之过
Kneeling right here
就在这儿跪着
Kneel until dawn tomorrow
跪到明天天亮为止
Seasonal medicine
季典药
What about purple duckweed
紫萍她们呢
Haven't you come back yet
还没有回来吗
You finally woke up after two days of lethargy
你昏睡了两天 终于醒了
Rest assured
放心
Since it is proved that your highness was born with gangrene,
既然证明殿下生的是背疽
Not poisoning
而非中毒
Will come back sooner or later
迟早会回来的
Yao palm meal
姚掌膳
The Crown Princess ordered you to deliver food
太子妃命你送膳
Crown Princess
太子妃
The handmaiden was ordered to deliver the meal
奴婢奉命来送膳
Do you know why I'm punishing you
知道我为何要罚你吗
You warn the queen
你向皇后示警
The surface is to remind the empress
表面是在提醒皇后娘娘
In fact, it is excusing the Shang Food Bureau
实则是在为尚食局开脱
But why did you say that second sentence
可你为何要说那第二句话呢
Hu Shang Shi
胡尚食
It's just rejected by the empress
不过是被皇后娘娘厌弃而已
So ah
所以啊
I'm just
我也不过
Is to make you kneel for half an hour
是让你跪了半个时辰而已
All right
好了
You can go now
你可以走了
This game
这一局
After all, I won
终究是我赢了
Zi Jin
子衿
I'm okay
我没事
I want to go in and have a rest
我想进去歇会儿
Injured
受伤了
And said no
还说没有
I saw it all
我都看到了
Take your hands out
把手拿出来
Let me check
让我看看
What are you doing
干什么呀
Hold out your hand
把手伸出来
Where else is it hurt
还伤在哪儿了
Leg
腿
I said I'm fine. Get up
我说了我没事 你起来
You let me have a look. Come on
你让我看一下 快点
Who told you to express your feelings to the queen
谁让你向皇后陈情的
Gong Zhengsi's staff responsibility
宫正司的杖责
Is that what you can stand
也是你能受得了的吗
Do you know that
你知不知道
Do you realize that you almost died yourself
你知不知道你自己差点没命了
That's enough
行了
Don't cry
不哭
Look
看
Am I alive and well now
我现在不是活得好好的吗
The Queen won't kill me yet
皇后现在还不会杀我
Who
谁
You come back, come back
你回来 回来
Don't cry
别哭了
I'm not crying
我才没哭
You're not crying yet
你还没哭
As soon as I came back, I heard that you went to Qingning Palace
我一回来就听说你去了清宁宫
Why are you so stupid
你为什么那么傻
To give up the crown prince
要将皇太子让出去
You sympathize with others everywhere
你处处同情别人
Why don't you pity yourself
你怎么不同情同情你自己
All right
好了
You cry so ugly
你哭得好丑
Purple Azolla
紫萍
They are all poor people, too
同样都是可怜的人
We have to fight each other
还要互相倾轧
Isn't it more pathetic
不是更加可悲吗
I only let it happen once
我只让一次
Just this once
就这一次
Okay
好吗
All right, stop crying
好了 不哭了
His Royal Highness the King of Wei His Royal Highness the King of Wei
卫王殿下 卫王殿下
It's not ready to start yet
起开 还没好呢
Be obedient
听话
Start and open
起开
You can't go to the fields yet
您现在还不能下地
Be obedient and obedient
听话 听话
Your Highness
殿下
It'll be ready in a minute
马上 马上就好了
You can't go to the fields yet
您现在还不能下地啊
His Royal Highness King Wei
卫王殿下
Zhan, what are you doing again
瞻埏 你又闹什么
I've been ill for so long
我病了这么久
Why didn't my mother come to see me
为什么母妃不来看我
I want to see my mother
我要见母妃
I'm going back soon
我马上就要回去
Nonsense
胡闹
Go back
回去
Sheng Taiyi worked hard
盛太医 辛苦了
Your Highness has spoken heavily
殿下言重了
This is the responsibility of Wei Chen
这是微臣分内之事
Sheng Taiyi's prescription about Wei Wang in these two days
盛太医 关于卫王这两日的药方
I was just about to ask you for advice
我正要向您请教
Yes
是
Xiao Shi
小十
Who allowed you to fool around like this
谁准你如此胡闹的
Brother, is my mother a bad woman
大哥 我母妃是坏女人吗
Who said that
谁说的
Everyone says she is a bad woman
人人都说她是坏女人
To frame the Queen
为了陷害皇后
Put my life at risk
置我的性命于不顾
Do you mean it
是真的吗
Now my father is angry
现在父皇生气了
Even he doesn't want me
连他也不要我
You won't come to see me, will you
不肯来看我了是吗
When you're asleep
你睡着的时候
Father has been here long ago
父皇早就来过了
It's just that he has something important to discuss now
只不过他现在有要事要商议
As for your mother concubine
至于你的母妃
When you are seriously ill,
在你病重的时候
She went to the temple to pray for you
她便去寺里为你祈福
That's why I couldn't be with you
所以才没能陪在你身边
Really
真的
When you are well,
等你病好了
Naturally, you will know whether it is true or false
自然就知道真假了
But
但是
If you keep being so disobedient,
你要是再这么不听话
I got angry.
我就生气了啊
That big brother will wait for me to get well
那大哥 等我病好了
Don't forget what you promised me
你答应我的事可不能忘记
I'm going to release the eagle
我要去放鹰
I also want to go hunting
我还想去狩猎
It's just
只是
Rest assured
放心
Big Brother will find the best doctor in the world
大哥会找这天底下最好的大夫
Treat you
为你治病
When you're ready
等你好了
Big Brother will take you hunting
大哥便带你去狩猎
Your Highness, I can't help it either
殿下 我也没法子啊
His Royal Highness the King of Wei refused to eat
卫王殿下闹着不肯吃饭
I have to go on asking questions
非要刨根问底地问下去
I this
我这
It can only be like this
也只能这样
Your Highness, I won't dare next time
殿下 我下次不敢了
There is too much gossip in your highness's palace
殿下 宫里流言蜚语太多
If someone intends to sow discord,
若有人成心挑拨离间
On the contrary, I will misunderstand you and the empress
反而会误会了您与皇后娘娘
It is better to tell the facts in advance
不如提前将事实相告
So as not to hurt brotherhood
免得伤了兄弟情谊
Guo Guifei has thousands of mistakes
郭贵妃纵是有千万个不对
She is also Ayan's mother
她也是阿埏的母亲
How can you say this to a child
你怎么能对一个孩子说这些
Even if you want to say
纵使要说
I will say it myself after recovery
也是等痊愈之后由我亲自说
Who allowed you to make your own decisions
谁准你自作主张
Your Highness, the handmaiden knew he was wrong
殿下 奴婢知错了
Handmaiden never dared again
奴婢再也不敢了
Your Highness, I will never dare again
殿下 我再也不敢了
Handmaiden knows wrong
奴婢知错了
You can go. You won't be needed in the future
你走吧 日后都用不着你了
Your Highness, the handmaiden followed you when he was six years old
殿下 奴婢六岁便跟着您
You are my God
您就是我的天啊
Where do you want me to go
您让我去哪儿啊
After you let me go
您让我走了以后
How can I stand on a cone
我哪有立锥之地啊
The handmaiden is wrong. The handmaiden is wrong
奴婢错了 奴婢错了
Handmaiden never dared again
奴婢再也不敢了
Never again, Your Highness
再也不敢了 殿下
Yuan Qi is also dedicated to thinking of his master
袁琦也是一心为主人着想
Will do something wrong
才会办错事
Why don't you spare him for my sake
不如看在我的分上饶了他吧
Yuan Qi
袁琦
In the future, you should be careful not to do it again
以后可要谨言慎行 不得再犯
Handmaiden never dared again
奴婢再也不敢了
If you do it again
如果再犯的话
He cut off the handmaiden's tongue
就割了奴婢的舌头
Go and get forty sticks
自去领四十杖
Thank you, Your Highness. Thank you, Your Highness
多谢殿下 多谢殿下
Get up quickly
快起来吧
Handmaiden will never forget the great kindness of the Crown Princess
奴婢不会忘记太子妃的大恩大德
Come
来
Right
对
Xiao Shi
小十
From now on
即日起
Yao Ziliao was officially promoted to Canon Food
姚子衿正式升任典膳
Yin Ziping is in charge of food
殷紫萍任掌膳之职
You should do your job well in the future
你们今后要好好办差
Yes
是
Han Ying's sister
含英姐姐
Let me see Meng Shang again
容我再见孟尚食一面吧
Don't transfer me to Shanglinyuan
不要调我去上林苑
I don't want to go there
我不想去那儿
Meng Shangshi, please don't drive me away
孟尚食 求您不要逐我走
Meng Shang Shi Please Meng Shang Shi
孟尚食 求求您了 孟尚食
Please, Meng Shangshi
求求您了 孟尚食
Please, please
求求您了
Do me a favor
帮我求个情吧
Please help me. Help me
求求你们帮帮我 帮帮我
Dare to ask Meng Shangshi
敢问孟尚食
What fault did she make when she heard the canon meal
闻典膳她是犯了什么过错
You're gonna kick her out
你要赶她走
Meritorious service should be rewarded and punished
有功该赏 有过必罚
Can define merits and demerits in the future
今后能够定义功过的
I am the only one in the food bureau
尚食局唯我一人
Do you all understand
你们都听明白了吗
Yes
是
According to Meng Shang's overbearing temper,
依照孟尚食霸道的性子
Get rid of Wen Yantao and don't even find a reason
赶走闻宴桃连个理由都不找
Those who go up to intercede now
现在上去求情的人
There must be no good fruit to eat
一定没好果子吃
That's enough
行了
Wen Yantao is eager for quick success and instant benefit
闻宴桃这个人急功近利
When Meng Shangshi was in trouble,
当初孟尚食落难时
She also deliberately made things difficult
她还蓄意刁难
She was transferred to Shanglinyuan at this time
她这个时候调去上林苑
Maybe it's a good thing
没准是件好事呢
Now Hu Shangshi has lost the support of the Queen
如今胡尚食失去了皇后的支持
Is to lose the greatest dependence
便是失去了最大的倚仗
People who take refuge in her in various departments
各司投靠她的人
Be denounced one by one
一个一个地遭到贬斥
You guess
你猜
Who will be the next person to be deported
下一个被驱逐的人会是谁呢
All right
好了
Zihao, I finally became a palm meal
子衿 我终于当上掌膳了
I'm on the palm. I'm on the palm
我是掌膳了 我是掌膳了
I am the palm meal
我是掌膳了
It's all like this
都这样了
Don't you find another backer
你还不另寻靠山
If it weren't for Monteggia
若非因为孟氏
Master can't be expelled from the palace
师父也不可能被逐出宫
I will never take refuge in the enemy
我绝不会投靠敌人的
Besides, it's not at the end of its tether
况且还未到山穷水尽
Why should you be so discouraged
您又何必如此气馁
You don't want to watch helplessly
您也不愿眼睁睁地
Watch the Shang Food Bureau fall back into the hands of Meng
看着尚食局重新落入孟氏之手吧
In this case
既然如此
Please wait patiently for the opportunity
还请您耐心等候时机
Please invite the imperial concubine to dinner
请贵妃娘娘用膳
The Queen is involved in this matter
此事牵涉皇后
I don't want to save you
我不欲搭救你
You face me now
你现在面对我
There is no resentment at all
竟然怨恨全无
Why
为什么
Please treat the empress to dinner
请娘娘用膳
Answer me
回答我
The imperial concubine did not give real trust
贵妃娘娘并未给予真正的信赖
Will be defeated so easily
才会如此轻易地落败
What's the use of grief at this point
事已至此 悲伤何用
Why don't you think about how to recover?
不如想一想如何复起
Dai Yuan has been sentenced to prison
戴院判已经下狱
A real disaster
真正的灾祸
It's just around the corner
就在眼前了
Empress
娘娘
It's better to fight hard than to wait and die
与其坐以待毙 不如奋力一搏
If the empress is willing to give me real trust
若娘娘肯给予我真正的信任
I will help you tide over the difficulties
我会帮您渡过难关
Wei Wang has recovered his health
卫王已经恢复康健
Just listlessness, poor appetite
只是精神不振 食欲不佳
His Royal Highness is very worried
太子殿下非常担心
Life is still in the food bureau, and everyone shows their strengths
命尚食局众人各展所长
Be sure to let Wei Wang resume eating
一定要让卫王恢复饮食
Yes
是
Meng Shangshi's orders just now
刚才孟尚食的吩咐
Everybody hear me clearly
大家都听清楚了
No matter what method is used,
不管用什么方法
Be sure to coax King Wei to eat
一定要哄着卫王用膳
Well done, the East Palace is rewarded
办得好 东宫重重有赏
If you don't do well, you can't escape punishment from top to bottom.
办不好 尚食局上下难逃责罚
Go quickly
快去吧
Yes
是
Jade, can you help me put that
玉脍 你帮我把那个
Yao canon meal
姚典膳
What meal are you going to prepare for King Wei
你预备给卫王准备什么膳食啊
Shall I help you
我来帮你好不好
No need
不必了
Since I decided to stay in the still food bureau,
既然决定留在尚食局
It is inevitable that there will be a contest between you and me
你我之间难免有较量
But do you know that
可你知不知道
I started entering the kitchen when I was five years old
我五岁时就开始进入厨房
Practice day and night every day
每天日以继夜地练
Can you argue with me
你能与我相争吗
Want to be a good cook
想成为一名好的庖厨
Let the world see the beauty of Chinese drinking
让世人看见中华饮馔之美
Do it if you want to
想做便做了
Famous chefs in the Forbidden City
紫禁城的名厨
And the chef of the rich and wealthy
还有豪门富户的厨娘
Street restaurants
街边的食店
A mother who cooks in a poor family
贫家做饭的母亲
Don't they all do the same thing
不都做着同样的事情吗
Divided into 369 for no reason
无故分为三六九等
It is also necessary to make judgments
还要妄加品评
This kind of state of mind has fallen into the lower multiplication
这样的心境本就落了下乘
Why don't you understand
怎么 听不懂啊
To put it bluntly, it's no better than
说直白点 不比
Fuck off
滚
Vulgar and unbearable
粗鄙不堪
Why are you so late
怎么来得这么迟啊
Wei Wang summoned
卫王召见
This is
这是
Handmaiden heard
奴婢听闻
Chrysanthemum into Pu'er can treat furuncle and swelling
以菊花入普洱能够治疗疔疮肿毒
It can also clear fire and improve eyesight
又可以清火明目
It is of great benefit to the health of His Royal Highness King Wei
对卫王殿下的身体大有好处
That's why I dared to give it a try
所以才斗胆一试
His Royal Highness King Wei
卫王殿下
To suit your taste
为了适合您的口味
The handmaiden also specially added a little rock sugar
奴婢还特地加了少许冰糖
It can eliminate the bitterness of chrysanthemums
可以消弭菊花的苦涩
Take a sip
喝一口
Try this crystal sweet-scented osmanthus cake
您尝尝这道水晶桂花糕
Osmanthus fragrans are picked by handmaidens
桂花是奴婢亲手采摘的
I hear that you often feel your heart burning
听闻您时常觉得心火旺
And sore throat
而且咽喉肿痛
This can alleviate
这个可以缓解
Or would you like to try steamed crab dumplings
或者您要不要尝尝蒸蟹饺
Your Highness, eat one
殿下 吃一个
I don't want to eat
我不想吃
Your Highness
殿下
Let's have a bite of crab dumplings
咱们呀 吃一口蟹饺
Look at this crab dumpling
你看这个蟹饺
This skin is so thin
这皮儿薄得呀
You can see the crab meat inside
里面的蟹肉都能看到
Every one is so full
每一个啊 都那么饱满
Particularly delicious
特别好吃
Come and have a bite
来 吃一口
Take a bite
吃一口嘛
I don't eat I don't eat
我不吃 我不吃
I just don't eat
我就是不吃
Good, good, don't eat, don't eat
好好好 不吃不吃
And sugar egg powder
还有糖蛋散
Crisp, crisp, sweet and delicious
酥酥脆脆 香甜可口
Ensure that the entrance is melted
保证入口即化
Eat it in your mouth
吃到嘴里啊
Can bite very delicate sugar silk
能咬到很细腻的糖丝儿
The mouth is full of thick egg fragrance
满嘴都是浓浓的蛋香味
This is a minister
这是臣呀
The sweetest and crispest cake you have ever eaten
吃到的最甜蜜 最香酥的糕点
Your Highness
殿下
I won't eat it
我就不吃
Your Highness, calm down. Your Highness, calm down
殿下息怒 殿下息怒
Your Highness, calm down
殿下息怒
Your Highness, this is called shrimp
殿下 此谓虾生
Please taste it, Your Highness
请殿下品尝
Your Highness and this
殿下 还有这个
Look how fun it is
您看 这多好玩啊
Eat one
吃一个
Are you juggling
你在变戏法吗
To coax me in such a ridiculous way
竟然用如此可笑的法子来哄我
Take it all away
全都拿走
Your Highness
殿下
Shrimp with unique flavor, handmaiden dares to offer it
虾生风味独特 奴婢斗胆献上
Handmaiden is guilty. Please forgive your highness
奴婢有罪 请殿下恕罪
Your Highness is not angry
殿下 不生气啊
Not angry
不生气
Your Highness
殿下
Please taste it, Your Highness
请殿下尝尝
Your Highness, look, this hedgehog is small
殿下 您看这个刺猬虽小
But it needs to be cut enough for 120 scissors
可足足要剪够一百二十剪呢
Bold
大胆
Your Highness has said everything
殿下都说了
Are you conjuring your highness
你在给殿下变戏法吗